

MR MOHAMMAD SHUJA-UL HODA

CBT Therapist, Interpersonal Therapist (IPT), Behavioural Couple Therapy Practitioner, and practice background in brain injury rehabilitation nursing.

Health City, Davenport House, 16 Pepper Street, Canary Wharf, London E14 9RP. Tel: 0333 800 3006, 0333 789 0012. Email: info@healthcity.org.uk,

Website: https://healthcity.org.uk/

As an experienced mental health worker I have gained twenty five years' worth of skills and knowledge working with adults suffering from mental health difficulties in the National Health Service (NHS from mild and moderate mental health problems to severe psychotic disorders, both in the statutory and community mental health sector. I am currently a BABCP Accredited Cognitive Behaviour Therapist as well as IPT UK accredited Interpersonal Therapist with significant experience of working in different IAPT settings. I have a special interest in Mindfulness and Compassion Focussed Therapy and am able to offer a professional, independent and collaborative service to clients and associated organisations. I am fluent in reading and writing English, Hindi, Urdu, as well working with Gujrati, and Punjabi clients. I also have excellent knowledge in computer skills including Microsoft Office and online platforms e.g. Zoom, Skype, MS Teams and WebEx.

Employment History:

Sept 2019 to present

Cognitive Behaviour Therapist, IPT Therapist and Behavioural Couple's Therapy Practitioner, Central and North West London NHS Trust (Harrow IAPT) part of a multidisciplinary team, as well as triaging new referrals. On top of my CBT and IPT accreditation, I have also recently completed a post-qualification certificate in Behavioural couple's therapy. I lead groups in areas such as Building Self Esteem. I also provide supervision to HI trainees and Qualified PWPs.

Feb 2010 - Aug 2019

Cognitive Behaviour Therapist/IPT Therapist, West London Mental Health NHS Trust (Ealing IAPT). I have acquired accredited status as an Interpersonal Therapist by IPT UK from 2013. I Work as part of a multidisciplinary team: screening, assessing and treating adults with mental health problems including depression, anxiety and phobias, post-traumatic stress disorder (PTSD) using high intensity cognitive behavioural therapy (CBT) and interpersonal therapy (IPT); Running groups as therapy sessions as well as in the community on Stress Management, Mindfulness, Anxiety Management and Anger Management; Providing supervision to junior staff.

Dec 2007-Sept 2008	Specialist Liaison , Eating Disorder Unit, St Anne's Hospital, London, Management of adults with Anorexia, Bulimia and Other Eating Disorders (EDNOS) in the community. Liaising with Hospital, Community Teams and other local services.
Oct 2000 - Nov 2007	Behaviour Therapist , Brain Injury Rehabilitation Unit, Edgware Hospital, Middlesex, HA8 0AD Assessing, managing and monitoring challenging behaviour of clients following acquired brain injury. Working within a multi-disciplinary team and training and advising staff on management of challenging behaviour.
Oct 1998 – Oct 2000	Staff Nurse (E - Grade), Brain Injury Rehabilitation Unit, Edgware Hospital, Edgware HA8 0AD
May 1996 - Oct 1998	Staff Nurse (D - Grade), Napsbury Hospital, St Albans

Education / Qualifications:

Dec 2018 – Jun 2019	Post-Qualification Certificate in Behavioural Couple's Therapy, Royal Holloway University.
Dec 2017 - Feb 2018	Supervision for HI Trainees, London CBT Training Centre.
Mar 2013 - Sept 2015	Interpersonal Therapy (IPT), Anna Freud Centre, London
Oct 2008 – Feb 2010	Postgraduate Diploma Cognitive Behavioural Therapy (IAPT Programme), Royal Holloway University of London.
Oct 1997 - June 2000	Clinical Hypnosis, Master Practitioner, Brief Strategic Therapy Foundation, London.
Sept 1993 - Feb 1996	Diploma of Higher Education in Nursing, University of Westminster, London.
Sept 1989 - June 1990	MA Clinical Psychology, Lucknow University, Lucknow India.
Jul 1984 – May 1987	BA Mathematics, Statistics and Economics, Lucknow University, Lucknow, India.

Presentations and Awards:

5th April 2011

The Collaboration for Leadership in Applied Health Research & Care (CLAHRC): Presentation on Improving

Access to Psychological Therapies for people of Ethnic Minority

Background.

5th April 2011

Award for the best project for PPI (Patient Public involvement): Engagement and reaching hard to reach communities.

Professional Registrations:

- IPT (UK)
- British Association for Behavioural and Cognitive Psychotherapies (BABCP).
- Nursing & Midwifery Council (NMC) as RMN
- General Hypnotherapy Register